thank you very very much and to my dear
dear friend
di
just I I
had although I'm not sure Tony if I said
all that quite correctly you'll have to
check out that latery is here with us
tonight
in that in americ English that does mean
congratulations on his very high honor
and I am highly honored to induct dig
Ross into the Cleveland International
Hall of Fame it seems that every few
years Di and I are reunited at some
awards ceremony and 5 years ago we were
both honored to serve as Slovenian man
and woman of the year but I have a
little confession to make
I the other half is Irish and so I wor
jacket but dck is the real deal he's
100% and he's married to the lovely
Chris who is Ukrainian and they have
three wonderful children three boys who
are double the Heritage a Stefan and
Pete and
two amazingly adorable baby boy
grandson and I have to tell you that
Dick's many many accomplishments which
I'm sure you have read and handry in the
booklet tonight nothing compares to the
love the accomplishment of his family
and I think dick will probably tell you
a little bit more about his
family well I have known dick for over
30 years and 15 of those 16 of those
years as coaker of fox mus at new
dick and I used to laugh and say we
think we are the we were in the longest
running Cleveland anchor team Cleveland
broadcast history and I think we still
are I don't think anyone has that and D
told you the story about the one thing
that is true we were for a period of
time the only all Slovenian team when we
had the addition of John tullich and Jan
PA
Jones but what she didn't say was during
the commercials we had boomx going here
playing po music
story well dick is being honored tonight
not just for his ethnic background but
because he truly embodies the spirit of
diversity in everything that he does
after di Left Channel 8 went to work at
Channel
3 and there was a slogan at that time in
channel 3 a b and wall in The Newsroom
that said report the facts respect the
truth
and that is the journalist that dick
Russ was he reported the facts he always
respected the truth and he respected
every individual whom he interviewed for
his
stories regardless of race of
creed of sex of ethnic background
cultural
background and mental
capacity dick Ross for betray every
individual in the light of dignity that
they
deserved so you might say how does a
full-blooded Slovenian boy get a name
like Russ for his last name well you
might not know this but his real last
name is lha begins with an h and that
silent well everyone knows that might
not make good teach right so we had to
pick another day so di chose
Russ and he chose Russ to honor
his brother
Russell Russell was a beautiful
beautiful man who lived his life with
mental
challenges and it was Dick's joy to be
devoted to
Russell and to care for him and to make
sure that he led a
productive healthy life that was filled
with
dignity and that's day
Ross when he left Channel
he moved to his career which he has now
as a vice president at North Coast
Community homes and he carries that
Spirit of helping to achieve dignity for
those less fortunate into his new role
his North Coast Community homes provides
housing support for those with mental
and physical
disabilities there are many people in
this room who know
dick and I know that you would join me
in saying that our line are better for
knowing dick and we are better people
for knowing dick
Russ and now you know something you may
not have known about his name so when
you hear the name dick Russ you will
know that it stands for a man of
character a man of integrity a man who
is kind gentle loving and most
importantly always chooses to find the
goodness in other people so ladies and
gentlemen my
[Applause]
pleas